Muhammad Ahsan Munir

Software Engineer

I have almost 5 years of experience if I'm excluding undergraduate internships then I have 4 years of experience in developing cross-platform mobile apps for iOS and Android using the react-native and expo library for many USA and European companies. I'm using state-of-the-art technologies such as redux, redux-saga, and redux-form to deliver reliable highly efficient, bug-free code within reasonable deadlines. Integration with various cloud technologies including Google Firebase, Google Map APIs, etc.



ahsanmuneer81@gmail.com



+923488300016



Karachi, Pakistan



11 November, 1996

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer - React Native Artistic Denim Mills (Fascom)

03/2022 - Present

Karachi, Pakistan

Responsibility/Tasks

- Developed front-end user interface using React Native and JavaScript for iOS and Android mobile applications.
- Successfully implemented features such as a camera module, push notifications, and a social media login.
- Improve front-end performance by eliminating performance bottlenecks.
- Implement clean, smooth animations to provide an excellent user interface.

Sr Executive Software Engineer

Outsource in Pakistan

03/2021 - 03/2022

Karachi, Pakistan

Achievements/Responsibility/Tasks

- Created animations and interactive components using React Native, including buttons, text fields, checkboxes, and radio buttons.
- Built a backend API for data storage using NodeJS and Express framework.
- Collaborated with designers on UI/UX design decisions and created mockups as needed.

React Native Developer

Linkitsoft

08/2020 - 03/2021

Karachi. Pakistan

Responsibility

• Develop and Design Android IOS mobile apps. Creating web and mobile APIs in Asp.net, Integrating Payment Systems like Gkash and Stripe payment. Also Integrating Firebase Cloud Messaging FCM, Push Notifications, Third-Party APIs Integrating and Google map APIs. Managing and Testing Mobile UI and UX.

SKILLS

Javascript

ES6

React

React Native

Redux

Github

HTML5

CSS3

Typescript

Nextjs

Material UI

Nodejs

Postman

Firebase Push Notification

Ant Design

Google Map APIs

Bootstrap

Firebase Realtime Database

EDUCATION

PIAIC (10/2022 - Present)

Certified Web 3.0 and Metaverse

Bachelor in Software Engineering (01/2016 - 11/2021) University of Karachi

LANGUAGES

Urdu

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

English

Professional Working Proficiency

CERTIFICATES

Certified Web 3.0 and Metaverse (10/2022 - Present)